# 早茶   江苏 扬州
Dim sum, Yangzhou, Jiangsu.
# 在扬州 有句话叫做“”
In Yangzhou, there is a saying ‘
# 这个皮包水 就是指的它的早茶
This ‘Pi Bao Shui’ (consommé wrapped in pastry) means Dim sum.
# 雪鱼现在在扬州
Xue Yu is in Yangzhou.
# 怎么能错过扬州这种特色的饮食文化呢
How can I miss this unique YangZhou food tasting opportunity?
# 走 跟着我去看看吧
Let’s go and take a look.
# 朝哪里走呢？
Where is the entrance?
# 到哪里点餐呢    到27号桌点餐
Where could I place the order? Table number 27 please.
# 上一桌的顾客刚离开
Previous diners just left.
# 桌布还没来得及铺好
The table is not ready yet.
# 现在是来的比较早吗
Is it still early (for dim sum)?
# 很多的老人家都是围坐着一个大桌
Many old folks sit around a big table.
# 大家热热闹闹地在这边喝早茶
They are enjoying dim sum here.
# 他们点了好多糕点 光小蒸笼都有那么高
They’ve ordered many dim sums. Look at the height of those bamboo steamers.
# 我觉得 他们光吃糕点就能吃到中午
I guess they don’t need anything else until lunch time.
# 因为我是第一次过来 来的时候给了一个小牌子
Since my first time here, I was given a card.
# 就是这个小牌子 它上面有二维码
This one, with a QR code.
# 早上应该按小牌子上的二维码点餐
I should have placed the order with this QR code in the morning.
# 但是我扫了它桌子上的二维码
But I scanned the QR code on the table instead.
# 然后被告知桌子上的二维码是中餐 晚餐用的
Then I was told that the QR code on the table is for lunch and dinner only.
# 早上扫它是不下单的
You cannot use it for breakfast.
# 现在的情况就是我们点了老半天的菜 不上菜
Now, it’s like nothing have shown up despite we placed an order ages ago.
# 我们要再重新下单
We need to place an order again.
# 而和我们同时来的另一桌  他们已经吃上了
Another table got their meal already despite we all arrived at the same time.
# 我们点餐的过程很艰难
Order processing is very slow.
# 现在呢 点了有蒸饺
Now. Here are steamed dumplings.
# 蟹黄汤包 他们这边的蟹黄汤包是很出名的 带汤的
Crab meat consommé in a bun. This place is renowned for this dish. It comes in consommé.
# 还有呢 就是松籽烧麦 三丁包 千层油糕
And, Siu Mai with pine nuts, steamed buns with three fillings, steamed layer cake.
# 听说 它这个千层油糕有64层 看一看
I heard there are 64 layers in steamed layer cake. Take a look.
# 还有这边比较出名的烫干丝
And a well-known dish, dried bean curd threads in consommé.
# 最后呢 还要了一壶的绿茶
Finally, a pot of green tea!
# 好了 下单了
Well, order is placed.
# 现在是89块钱
It’s RMB89.
# OK了
# 这个就是扬州早茶当中最特色的 烫干丝
This is the most unique dish in Yangzhou’s dim sums, dried bean curd threads in consommé.
# 我点的这个是小份的 12块钱
I ordered a small portion, RMB12.
# 看着就是酱油的颜色 闻着还有香油的味道
The colour looks like soy sauce. It also smells sesame oil.
# 看着浓油赤酱的样子 会觉得它很咸
By the look of it, it may be quite salty.
# 尝一尝是不是和自己想的（味道）是一样的
See what it tastes like…
# 一点都不会觉得咸
It’s not salty at all!
# 但是香油的味道确实是很重的
But there is a strong hint of sesame oil.
# 烫干丝啊烫干丝 就是用白豆腐干
Dried bean curd threads in consommé. It threads white
# 切成丝 然后在沸水当中烫完
dry bean curd, then blanch them in boiling water.
# 再加上虾米 酱油等来调味
Season with dried shrimps, soy sauce and other ingredients.
# 干丝吃起来是既细又柔软
Texture is so fine and soft.
# 蟹黄汤包
Crab meat consommé in a bun.
# 哦 给了一个吸管
A straw.
# 用筷子一敲 就觉得它肯定是个水货（肚里有汤）
Tap it with a chopstick. There must be consommé inside.
# 里面的汤 很多啊
So much!
# 用筷子一敲
Tap, tap.
# 啊 汤出来了
Oops, it leaked.
# 我不是故意的 我只是想敲一敲它
I didn’t do it on purpose. I just want to tap it.
# 正常应该是用吸管 戳个洞
Usually you use straw to poke a hole,
# 然后吸着汤汁来吃的
then suck the consommé out.
# 但是 我刚才用筷子 我只是想动一动它 然后
But I only touched it with chopsticks, and
# 它的汤汁就全出来了
the consommé all come out.
# 现在 我就是被迫要先吃它了
Now, I have to eat it first.
# 哎呀 这么吃着 感觉幸福感就降低了很多
Hmmm, this way has much less fun of enjoyment.
# 我把吸管插到了汤包的面皮上了 根本就吸不上来
My straw sticks inside the pastry. I cannot suck it up!
# 这是翻车事件
This is a disaster!
# 它这个就是鸡汤和蟹黄 融合在一起的感觉
It feels like the combination of chicken stock and crab meat.
# 吃起来有点腥味
It tastes a bit of fishy.
# 我本来为它准备了很多的台词
Originally, I had a lot to say.
# 和它搭配着要演很多的戏
And expect a lot of fun with it.
# 现在呢 它只能被迫离场了
Now, it is done and dusted.
# 这一拿上来就是能够闻到很重的面香
The fragrance of steamed flour is so strong.
# 这一笼呢 就是两个千层油糕
There are two steamed layer cakes in the steamer.
# 蒸饺 一个单独的豆沙包
Steamed dumplings. An individual red bean paste bun.
# 我还有一笼 这一笼一共有两种
Here is another one. There are two varieties.
# 一个是松子烧麦
One is Siu Mai with pine nuts.
# 能够看到里面（冒出头）的糯米
You can see the gluten rice coming out on the top.
# 这个呢 就是三丁包
This one is buns with three fillings.
# 这次我是点了三丁包 没有点五丁
I ordered three fillings instead of five this time.
# 五丁呢 就是在三丁包的基础上会增加虾丁还有参丁
Five fillings will have additional diced shrimps and sea cucumber.
# 能够看到里面 鸡肉丁 笋丁还有猪肉丁
You can see there are diced chicken, bamboo shoots and pork inside.
# 它的外皮特别暄软 里面的肉汤 已经浸入到面皮当中了
The bun is extremely soft. The pastry is soaked with juice.
# 吃起来就是咸当中还有一些甜味
There is a hint of sweetness in this savoury dish.
# 还有笋丁脆脆的口感
And the taste of crunchiness from bamboo shoots.
# 它这个就是 每层之间 会有这个糖油层
There is a coating of sugar and oil mixture between each layer.
# 上面加了一些青红丝 这么点缀着就是更加好看一些
It is topped with some finely sliced green and red peppers. The dressing makes it more attractive.
# 糖的味道还是很突出的
Sugar taste is particularly strong.
# 它的甜 没有让你觉得很油腻
It is sweet, but not sickening.
# 吃起来也是这种很松软 很暄软的口感
The feeling is soft and moist.
# 本来一口是放不下的
It looks too big for a mouthful.
# 但是 里面有很多的空隙
But it is very light.
# 一口就可以吃掉很大一块的千层油糕
You can bite a big chunk off.
# 你看 我今天点的蟹黄汤包 还有三丁包是有点油的
The crab meat consommé bun and buns with three fillings are savoury.
# 而像千层油糕 是有点甜的
Whereas layered cake is sweet.
# 但不管是油腻 还是甜腻
Whether it is savoury or sweet,
# 都可以喝杯茶解腻
can all be washed done with a cup of cha!
# 还有 我今天来吃早茶的地方 是很金碧辉煌的
Anyway, I came to a resplendent and magnificent place for dim sum today.
# 这一层 有几十张桌子
There are dozens of tables on this floor.
# 来的时候 都坐得满满的
It was full when I came.
# 不过 如果我们的座位被安排到窗边会更好
It would be nice if we could sit next to the windows.
# 它那边的窗户都是落地的
They are all French windows.
# 可以看到外面的景色
You can view outside.
# 这种的感觉 才是最好的吧
The dining experience would be brilliant!
# 来到扬州的早茶店 我才知道 原来茶叶是可以自带的
After dim sum, I just realised that I could bring my own tea leaves here.
# 很多人呢 就是拿着自己的小水杯 里面放着茶叶
Many diners carry their own little cups with tea leaves inside.
# 用这边的开水
The restaurant provides boiling water.
# 再点个小点心就可以了
All they need is a few dim sums.
# 下次 我也要试一试
I want to try it next time as well.
# 在扬州 走着走着就能发现 一汪清水 还有一个小亭子
In Yangzhou, you can frequently find a small pond and a small pavilion during your walk about.
# 清水里面有花草 就会显得周围的环境格外雅致
The flowers and plants in the pond give the surrounding a more elegant feel.
# 关  注
# 雪 鱼  探 店
Be sure to follow China Food Travel